(301)531-0487 New Haven, Connecticut tsimosyiorgos@gmail.com

Georgios Tsimos

PhD Candidate in Cryptography

Website, Google Scholar LinkedIn: gtsimos

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

University of Maryland, College Park

Aug 2019- Present (exp. December 2024)

Advisor: Professor Charalampos Papamanthou (at Yale)

Co-Advisor: Professor Jonathan Katz (at UMD)

M.Sc. in Electrical Engineering exp. Aug. 2024

University of Maryland, College Park

M.Sc. in COMPUTER SCIENCE Athens University of Economics and Business, Greece B.Sc. (4-year Ptychion) in COMPUTER SCIENCE Athens University of Economics and Business, Greece Oct 2018- July 2019 9.44/10.0 (Honors)

submitted

While at Yale

manuscript

Oct 2014 - Sept 2018

8.79/10.0 (Honors, Valedictorian)

ABOUT

I am a PhD Student co-advised by Charalampos Papamanthou and Jonathan Katz, at the Electrical Engineering department at the University of Maryland. Currently I am a Visiting Assistant in Research (VAR) at Yale CS. My research interests include several aspects of applied Cryptography, such as Byzantine Consensus and Blockchains, secure Multi-Party Computation, Verifiable Secret Sharing and more.

My ongoing research projects include new techniques for more resource-efficient Byzantine Consensus protocols and practical improvements of efficiency metrics in Blockchains.

During my undergrad, my research focus was in Theoretical CS topics, including Logic and Computational Complexity.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Research Intern May 2024- Present

Chainlink Labs Remote

Research Intern in Distributed Systems May 2023- August 2023

MystenLabs Remote

Visiting Assistant Researcher in COMPUTER SCIENCE Dec 2022- Present Yale University New Haven, CT

Visiting Researcher Dec 2022 CISPA Helmholtz Center for Information Security Saarbrücken, Germany

Graduate Research Assistant Aug. 2019 — Present

University of Maryland, College Park, MD Maryland Cybersecurity Center (MC2 Lab)

PUBLICATIONS

D. Collins and S. Duan and J. Loss and C. Papamanthou and G. T. and H. Wang:

"Towards Optimal Parallel Broadcast under a Dishonest Majority"

A. Alexandru and J. Loss and C. Papamanthou and G. T. and B. Wagner:

"Sublinear-Round Broadcast without Trusted Setup"

submitted G. T. and A. Tsichidis and A. Sonnino and L. Kokoris-Kogias: New! While at MystenLabs

"HammerHead: Leader Reputation for Dynamic Scheduling" Accepted! ICDCS 2024

F. Elsheimy and G. T. and C. Papamanthou:

Accepted! SODA 2024 "Deterministic Byzantine Agreement with Adaptive $O(n \cdot f)$ Communication"

A. Alexandru and J. Loss and C. Papamanthou and G. T.: "Sublinear-Round Broadcast without Trusted Setup against Dishonest Majority"

G. T. and J. Loss and C. Papamanthou:

"Gossiping For Communication-Efficient Broadcast" Accepted! CRYPTO 2022

HONORS AND AWARDS

STUDENT TRAVEL GRANT (\$650) January 2024

SIAM, SODA DEAN'S FELLOWSHIP (\$15.000) Aug. 2019 — Jun. 2020

for the First Year of Ph.D.

University of Maryland, College Park, MD June 2022

OUTSTANDING ACADEMIC PERFORMANCE SCHOLARSHIP (\$5,000) **Gerondelis Foundation**

AWARD IN MEMORY OF MICHALIS MITILINAIOS 2016-2017

for *Top Performance* in selected TCS courses AUEB, Greece

SKILLS

Communication: English (fluent speaker), Greek (native), Spanish (basic communication)

VOLUNTARY ACTIVITIES AND SERVICE TO THE COMMUNITY

External Subreviewer for JoC'24, Financial Crypto'24, AFT'23, CCS'23, PKC'23, Financial Crypto'23, CCS'22, EuroCrypt'21

REFERENCES

Associate Professor Charalampos (Babis) Papamanthou (at Yale), (Ph.D Advisor): charalampos.papamanthou@yale.edu
Assistant Professor Julian Loss (at CISPA), (Research Collaborator): lossjulian@gmail.com
Assistant Professor Lefteris Kokoris-Kogias (at IST Austria, Mysten Labs), (Internshiph Advisor): lefteris@mystenlabs.com